<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Space on hi, I am robin</title><link>https://robamu.github.io/tags/space/</link><description>Recent content in Space on hi, I am robin</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 23:12:59 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://robamu.github.io/tags/space/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Implementing a TCP server for Space Applications in Rust using the Strategy Pattern</title><link>https://robamu.github.io/blog/rust-strategy-pattern/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 15:17:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://robamu.github.io/blog/rust-strategy-pattern/</guid><description>&lt;p>Even for space systems, TCP/IP is oftentimes an important component in some shape or form because
the majority of development might still occur on ground where an internet connection is still
available. The special thing about space is that instead of using newline and/or UTF-8 based
data, the data is generally in binary format and packet based. The most prevalent of the space
packet standards is probably the &lt;a href="https://public.ccsds.org/Pubs/133x0b2e1.pdf">CCSDS Space Packet Protocol&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bringing Rust to Space - Setting up a Rust ecosystem for the VA108XX MCU family</title><link>https://robamu.github.io/blog/rust-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 23:31:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://robamu.github.io/blog/rust-ecosystem/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="update-2024">UPDATE 2024&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I have recently converted the VA108xx Rust support into monocrates which can now be found
&lt;a href="https://egit.irs.uni-stuttgart.de/rust/va108xx-rs">here&lt;/a>. I have also started working on the
support for the VA416XX family of devices which can be found &lt;a href="https://egit.irs.uni-stuttgart.de/rust/va416xx-rs">here&lt;/a>.
The new repositories also now use the &lt;code>embedded-hal&lt;/code> v1 release.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="blogpost">Blogpost&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The last few weeks I have been busy diving into the Rust ecosystem and learning the language
through practical projects. I finishing the excellent
&lt;a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/book/">Rust book&lt;/a> and the &lt;a href="https://docs.rust-embedded.org/book/">Rust Embedded Book&lt;/a>
first and then tinkered with Rust on some STM32 MCUs. As a next step, I was looking for practical
projects to further learn the language. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to combine this with the usual activities at
the research institute I work now as well.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>